Guide to the Ron Whyte Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1957-1989; Series V; 13; (13 boxes)
  - Disability Organizations A-H, 1978 September 6, undated (Box 107)
  - Disability Organizations I-P, 1978, undated (Box 107)
  - Disability Organizations Q-Z, 1978 (Box 107)
  - Brewer, Curtis, 1978, undated (Box 107)
  - Birmingham Festival Theatre. Handicapped Playright Residency (1978-79), 1977-1978 (Box 107)
  - Dorothy Shaw, 1978 (Box 107)
  - Birmingham Project, 1977-1978, undated (Box 107)
  - Money Orders (empty leaves), undated (Box 107)
  - Media - Press Books, undated (Box 107)
  - Media / Television, 1961 (Box 107)
  - Media / Special Events, undated (Box 107)
  - Media / Film, undated (Box 107)
  - Ron To Do, 1980, undated (Box 107)
  - Contact List for Project with Addenda Letters, undated (Box 107)
  - The Marriage of Bette and Boo by Christopher Durang, Directed by Steve Zuckerman, 1979 November 5 (Box 107)
  - Force of Habit by Thomas Bernhard, translated and directed by Michael Feingold, 1979 October 23 (Box 107)
  - 1979 correspondence from unit [Actors Studio] (Box 107)
  - Playrights & Directors Project, undated (Box 107)
  - Playrights & Directors Project. Ron's notes, undated (Box 107)
  - For Ron only, 1979 January, undated (Box 107)
  - Higher Crit. B. S. I., undated (Box 108)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 108)
  - Projects: Gregory Battcock, 1975; 2 (Box 108)
  - M. Dorson, undated (Box 108)
  - Advertising Workshop, 1976 (Box 108)
  - Tract advertising, undated (Box 108)
  - Carbon paper, undated (Box 108)
  - Letters Page Thesis, 1966, undated (Box 108)
  - Notes on Marvel, undated (Box 108)
  - Marvel Annuals - Notes, outlines (empty folder), undated (Box 108)
  - Western plots (empty folder), undated (Box 108)
  - Thor outlines (empty folder), undated (Box 108)
  - Western Books - notes, outlines (empty folder), undated (Box 108)
  - Avengers - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Thor - outline, undated (Box 108)
  - Nick Fury - Shield, undated (Box 108)
  - Journey into Mystery - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Western Plots, undated (Box 108)
  - Rawhide Kid, undated (Box 108)
  - Sgt. Fury - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Kid Colt, undated (Box 108)
  - X-Men -outlines-, undated (Box 108)
  - Motion pictures - articles, 1977 September 25 (Box 108)
  - Movies - Scatological. J. Waters, 1977, undated (Box 108)
  - National Book Awards, 1977 (Box 108)
  - Happiness Cage / Reviews, copies, undated (Box 108)
  - Newport, John P., 1977 June 20 (Box 108)
  - New York Film Festival, 1977 (Box 108)
  - New York Public Library, 1977 (Box 108)
  - Sermonettes, undated; 2 (Box 108)
  - Cato, undated (Box 108)
  - A Ringing in the Ears, undated (Box 108)
  - R. W. - Personal Files, 1982 (Box 108)
  - Bibliography / Reference, undated (Box 108)
  - Racism, undated (Box 108)
  - R. W. - Vitae, 1984 (Box 108)
  - Home File, 1979, undated (Box 108)
  - New American Theatre, 1984, undated (Box 108)
  - Amy Saltz, 1978-1979 (Box 108)
  - Horatio / Washington, D. C. originals, 1974-1978, undated (Box 108)
  - Disability - 12/78. Press clips, 1978 December (Box 108)
  - Kee Young, undated (Box 108)
  - Martin, Sandy, undated (Box 108)
  - Access / Communication, 1984 (Box 108)
  - Romance Books - Notes, outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Fantastic Four - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Tales of Asgard, undated (Box 108)
  - Iron Man - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Captain America - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Dare Devil - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Letters Pages, undated (Box 108)
  - Spiderman - outlines, undated (Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 108)
  - Cover - Copy, undated (Box 108)
  - Violations of Marvel, undated (Box 108)
  - Limrick - Limericksys - Limerackies, undated (Box 108)
  - Comic Book Plots, undated (Box 108)
  - Submarine R - T. V. Series -, undated (Box 108)
  - Center for Human Policy - Articles, Syracuse, 1974-1977, undated; 2 (Box 108)
  - Allard Lowenstein Anthology, 1980 (Box 108)
  - Theatre Group. Notebook: Digests of Source Books, undated (Box 108)
  - Comics, circa 1976-1981; 2 (Box 108)
  - Comics, 1964-1980, undated; 30 (Box 109)
  - Comics, undated; 2 (Box 110)
  - First Annual Integrated Young Playright Festival, 1984; 3 (Box 110)
  - Resume, undated (Box 110)
  - Apartment, circa 1965-1987; 3 (Box 110)
  - Soho News, 1977, undated (Box 110)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers, 1978-1988, undated; 2 (Box 110)
  - Banking, circa 1976-1985; 3 (Box 110)
  - Gregory Battcock, 1972-1974, undated; 2 (Box 110)
  - Books owned, undated (Box 110)
  - Dr. W. Bradley, 1969-1983 (Box 110)
  - Ruth Hagy Brod, 1980-1983 (Box 110)
  - Budget, Welfare info, 1979-1987, undated (Box 110)
  - Fabiano Canosa, 1972 December 27 (Box 110)
  - Creative Artists Public Service Program, 1980-1981 (Box 111)
  - Jean Cocteau: Materials: Random, undated (Box 111)
  - Cohen & Grossberg, 1970-1972 (Box 111)
  - Connecticut Coordinating Committee of the Handicapped, 1985-1986 (Box 111)
  - Connecticut Income Assistance, 1984-1986, undated (Box 111)
  - Cultural Council Foundation, undated (Box 111)
  - Transportation Project, 1975 (Box 111)
  - The Dramatists Guild, Inc., 1972-1983, undated (Box 111)
  - Exlectix - Lee McClure, [1986]; 2 (Box 111)
  - Eric Ruff, 1973-1981 (Box 111)
  - Fire Escape Theatre, [1972] (Box 111)
  - Funding, circa 1968-1989; 2 (Box 111)
  - Kennedy Center, 1983-1985 (Box 111)
  - Lawsuit Medical, 1983-1985 (Box 111)
  - Lucy Kroll, 1975-1977 (Box 111)
  - Disability lawsuit, 1983, undated (Box 111)
  - Helen Merril, 1982-1983 (Box 111)
  - Ellen Neuwald, 1974 February 27, undated (Box 111)
  - Moos, Charles, 1974 (Box 111)
  - Press Releases, 1982-1983 (Box 111)
  - Receipts, 1981 December 5, undated (Box 111)
  - The Lexington Press, 1981 (Box 111)
  - Ed Katz, 1978 June 19 (Box 111)
  - Lee Marvin, 1966 March 30 (Box 111)
  - Riverside Church, 1994 (Box 111)
  - National Cristina Foundation, 1994 June 6 (Box 111)
  - Omega One, 1983, undated (Box 111)
  - List of phone calls to be made, undated (Box 111)
  - Phone messages, [1980] (Box 111)
  - Phone scripts, [1982]-1984 (Box 111)
  - Film proposal, undated (Box 111)
  - Pulitzer Prize nomination, undated (Box 111)
  - Pulp magazines, undated (Box 111)
  - Press Releases, undated (Box 111)
  - Religious Community for the Arts, undated (Box 112)
  - Soho News, 1978, undated (Box 112)
  - Time keeping, 1973 December 30, undated (Box 112)
  - Union Bills, 1973-1975, undated (Box 112)
  - Vitae, 1982-1984 (Box 112)
  - Worth, Irene, 1967 May 20 (Box 112)
  - Writers Guild, 1969-1988 (Box 112)
  - Workshops in Residence, 1979, undated (Box 112)
  - Michael Ewing lawsuit, 1984, undated (Box 112)
  - After death, 1990 (Box 112)
    Includes 3 audiocassettes
    Use of original audiocassettes is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Amerikan Climax Clothing, undated (Box 112)
- Personal Papers, 1950-1989; Series VI; 8.04; (10 boxes)
  Organized roughly by type of material.
  Series VI consists of appointment and address books, phone messages, financial records, drawings, and other papers and ephemera that document Ron Whyte's personal life.
  - Appointment books, 1977-1984; 9 (Box 113)
  - Appointment books, 1984-1986; 5 (Box 114)
  - Diary, 1955-1972; 4 (Box 114)
  - Diary, 1984, undated; 2 (Box 115)
  - Phone messages, 1983 November-December, undated; 4 (Box 115)
  - Address book, undated (Box 115)
  - Financial records, circa 1973-1985; 5 (Box 115)
  - Financial records, circa 1973-1985; 8 (Box 115)
  - Social Services, 1978 August (Box 115)
  - Guest books, 1989, undated; 2 (Box 116)
  - Address labels, undated (Box 116)
  - Travel kit, 1950 (Box 116)
  - Calendar, 1976 (Box 116)
  - Certificate of Baptism, undated (Box 116)
  - Receipts, 1974, undated; 4 (Box 116)
  - Medical records, undated (Box 116)
  - Medical records, circa 1971-1979; 2 (Box 117)
  - Notes and notebooks, undated; 25 (Box 117)
  - Notes and notebooks, undated; 21 (Box 118)
  - Notes and notebooks, 1978, undated; 3 (Box 119)
  - Phone book, undated (Box 119)
  - Stationery paper, undated; 5 (Box 119)
  - Drawings by Ron Whyte, undated; 13 (Box 119)
  - Curriculum Vitae, circa 1974-1983; 6 (Box 119)
  - Architectural blueprint, 1978 December 28 (Box 120)
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 120)
  - Red pillow, undated (Box 120)
  - Ungar-Craft woodburning pencil and artwork, undated (Box 120)
  - Identification cards and business cards, 1964-1978, undated (Box 120)
  - Comics figurine, undated (Box 120)
  - Address cards from rolodex, undated; 5 (Box 121)
  - Address cards from rolodex, undated; 3 (Box 122)
- Printed Material, 1939-1985; Series VII; 5; (5 boxes)
  Series VII consists of clippings, articles, and photocopies of printed material relating to Ron Whyte and to cultural and literary topics that intersect with his writing and work.
  - Printed material, circa 1954-1987; 29 (Box 123)
  - Printed material, circa 1933-1981; 31 (Box 124)
  - Printed material, circa 1965-1981; 30 (Box 125)
  - Printed material, circa 1939-1985; 24 (Box 126)
  - Clippings, 1971-1985; 30 (Box 127)
- Photographs, 1953-1991; Series VIII; 1; (1 box)
  Not arranged in any particular order
  Series VIII consists of photographic prints and slides relating to Ron Whyte's personal and professional life and include portraits of actors, snapshots of dramatic performances and rehearsals, and snapshots of Ron Whyte, and family and friends of Ron Whyte. Most subjects of photographs are not identified.
  - Photographs of dramatic performances, 1974-1979, undated; 5 (Box 128)
  - Portraits of actors, 1972, undated; 6 (Box 128)
  - Portraits of Ron Whyte, 1964-1989, undated; 10 (Box 128)
  - Portrait of James Purdy, undated (Box 128)
    Includes Purdy's article "The Violet Velvet Violence"
  - Portrait of Oscar Lewis, undated (Box 128)
  - Photographs of family and friends, 1953-1990, undated; 10 (Box 128)
  - WPC Art Project, 1964 (Box 128)
  - Unsorted photographs, 1965-1978, undated; 4 (Box 128)
  - Hunchback / New Hampshire (slides), 1980 (Box 128)
  - Montana - Disability Consciousness raising (slides), 1978 (Box 128)
  - Unsorted slides, 1973-1991, undated; 2 (Box 128)
- Unsorted Papers, circa 1967-1990; Series IX; 7.42; (8 boxes)
  Series IX consists of unsorted notes, correspondence, ephemera, and printed material.
  - Unsorted papers, circa 1973-1981; 30 (Box 129)
  - Unsorted papers, circa 1975-1990; 19 (Box 130)
  - Unsorted papers, circa 1972-1989; 21 (Box 131)
  - Unsorted papers, 1973-1982, undated; 19 (Box 132)
  - Unsorted papers, circa 1973-1989; 19 (Box 133)
  - Unsorted papers, circa 1967-1988; 24 (Box 134)
  - Unsorted papers, circa1968-1984; 20 (Box 135)
  - Unsorted papers, 1976-1978, undated; 3 (Box 136)
- Audiovisual Material, circa 1973-1980; Series X; 12.92; (31 boxes)
  Organized by format.
  Series X consists chiefly of recordings of productions of dramatic performances, presumably of works written or produced by Ron Whyte. Many tapes include identifying information on their boxes.
  Boxes 138-159 (reel-to-reel audiotapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 160-167 (record albums, audiocassettes, and videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Guides to audiotapes, 1973-1974; 14 (Box 137)
  - Reel-to-reel audiotapes
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 138)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 139)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (10 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 140)
    - "Horatio - Arena", 1974 Summer; 1 (Box 140)
    - "Songs - Whyte/McClure", undated; 1 (Box 140)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 141)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 142)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 143)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 144)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 145)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 146)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 147)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 148)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 149)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 150)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (12 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 151)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 152)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 153)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 154)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 155)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 156)
    - Production recordings, 1970s; (11 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 157)
    - Production recordings and concerts, 1970s; (18 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 158)
    - Production recordings and concerts, 1970s; (14 reel-to-reel audiotapes) (Box 159)
  - Record Albums
    - Music recordings, 1973-1974, undated; (22 7" record albums) (Box 160 (Record Album Storage))
  - Audiocassettes
    - Production recordings and phone messages, 1978-1980, undated; (34 audiocassettes) (Box 161)
    - Production recordings, 1980s; (37 audiocassettes) (Box 162)
    - Production recordings, 1980s; (36 audiocassettes) (Box 163)
    - Production recordings, 1985, undated; (35 audiocassettes) (Box 164)
    - Other recordings, 1974-1979, undated; (28 audiocassettes) (Box 165)
    - "Find Me" by Olwen Wymark & "Hot Dogs and Soda Pop" by Thomas Babe, 1980 April 14; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 166)
    - "Readings / Performance Tapes, Vol. One", 1978-1979, undated; (9 audiocassettes) (Box 166)
    - "Tapes / Whyte Plays, Vol. Two", 1979-1980; (6 audiocassettes) (Box 166)
    - "2 Performances of Funeral March for a One-Man Band - May 1978 Westbeth", 1978 May; (6 audiocassettes) (Box 166)
  - Videocassettes
    - "Birmingham Festival Theatre," producer Billy D. Hunter, unedited master copy, tape 1 of 2, undated; YCALMSS670_0003; 1; 00:50:25 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002102310647)
    - "Birmingham Festival Theatre," producer Billy D. Hunter, unedited master, tape 2 of 2, undated; YCALMSS670_0004; 1; 00:23:35 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002102310654)
    - "Lullabye / Antonia" 2 versions, camera left: Lisa brother, camera right: Suzanne, undated; YCALMSS670_0005; 1; 00:34:08 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002102310662)
- Oversize Material, 0.83; (4 boxes)
  - Drawings (from Series VI), undated (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - Union Theological Seminary (from Series III), 1976 May 21 (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - Hugo articles (from Series IV), undated; 2 (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - Photographs of dramatic performances (from Series VIII), undated; 2 (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - Portrait of Ron Whyte (from Series VIII), undated (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - Printed material (from Series VII), 1964-1982, undated; 6 (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - Printed material (from Series VII), undated; 4 (Box 169 (Oversize))
  - Lee McClure (from Series IV), undated (Box 169 (Oversize))
  - Printed material (from Series VII), undated (Box 170 (Oversize))
  - Music scores (from Series II), undated; 2 (Box 170 (Oversize))
  - Printed material (from Series VII), 1981, undated; 3 (Box 171 (Oversize))
  - Music scores (from Series II), undated; 2 (Box 171 (Oversize))
  - Reviews (from Series II), 1981 (Box 171 (Oversize))
  - American Book Review (from Series III), undated (Box 171 (Oversize))
  - Comics (from Series IV), undated (Box 171 (Oversize))